( theme music playing )
♪ Game of Thrones 6x01 ♪
The Red Woman
Original Air Date on April 24, 2016
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
♪  ♪
♪ Music playing ends  ♪
( wind blowing )
( wolf howling )
( howling continues )
( door rattles )
( door rattling )
( wolf whimpering )
( rattling continues )
( howling continues )
( Ghost whimpering,
howling )
- ( rattling continues )
- ( whimpering, howling continue )
Man: It's coming
from the courtyard.
- ( Ghost howling )
- Man #2: It's the Lord Commander!
Help me get him inside.
( howling continues )
( door closes )
Thorne did this.
How many of your brothers
do you think you can trust?
Trust?
The men in this room.
Davos:
Does the wolf know you?
We need all the help
we can get.
( knocking on door )
Melisandre:
Ser Davos.
( door closes )
Melisandre:
I saw him in the flames
fighting at Winterfell.
I can't speak
for the flames...
but he's gone.
( men shouting )
Man:
He was our Lord Commander.
Man #2:
He never should have been!
( pounds )
- You all know why you're here.
- ( shouting stops )
( men murmuring )
Jon Snow is dead.
Who killed him?
- I did.
- ( shouting resumes )
And Bowen Marsh
and Othell Yarwyck
and the other officers
in this castle.
- Murderers!
- Traitors!
- ( men shouting )
- ( pounds on table )
- You're right!
- ( shouting stops )
We've committed treason,
all of us.
Jon Snow was
my Lord Commander.
I had no love for him.
That was no secret.
But I never once
disobeyed an order.
Loyalty is the foundation
on which the Night's
Watch is built.
And the Watch means
everything to me.
I have given my life,
we have all given our lives
to the Night's Watch.
Jon Snow was going to destroy
the Night's Watch.
He let the wildlings
through our gates
as no Lord Commander
has ever done before.
He gave them the very land
on which they reaved
and raped and murdered.
Lord Commander Snow
did what he thought was right,
I've no doubt
about that.
And what he thought was right
would have been the end of us.
He thrust a terrible
choice upon us.
And we made it.
( men murmuring )
( whimpering )
Davos: He'll have seen
we didn't come.
Thorne will have
made it official by now.
Castle Black is his.
I don't care who's sitting
at the high table.
Jon was my friend.
And those fuckers
butchered him.
Now we return the favor.
We don't have
the numbers.
- We have a direwolf.
- It's not enough.
I didn't know
Lord Commander Snow for long,
but I have to believe he wouldn't have
wanted his friends to die for nothing.
If you were planning to see tomorrow,
you picked the wrong room.
We all die today.
I say we do our best
to take Thorne with us when we go.
We need to fight,
but we don't need to die.
- Not if we have help.
- Who is gonna help us?
You're not the only ones
who owe your lives to Jon Snow.
Bolt the door.
Don't let anyone in.
I'll be back
as soon as I can.
( door closes )
( bolt clicks )
( wind howling )
Ramsay: She was 11 the first time
I saw her.
The kennelmaster's
daughter.
She smelled of dog.
I wasn't much older,
but everybody was already afraid of me.
You certainly were.
Myranda wasn't, though.
What could I do to her
that those hounds couldn't?
She was fearless.
There was nothing
she wouldn't do.
Your pain will be paid for
a thousand times over.
I wish you could
be here to watch.
Maester: Shall I have a grave
dug for her, my lord?
Or would you rather
the men build a pyre?
Buried, burned?
This is good meat.
Feed it to the hounds.
Roose: Your command of the cavalry
was impressive.
Thanks to you, the false king
Stannis Baratheon is dead.
Do you know who struck
the killing blow?
- No.
- A shame.
I'd reward the man.
Still,
a great victory.
Do you feel
like a victor?
I rebelled
against the crown
to arrange your marriage
to Sansa Stark.
Do you think that
burning wagons in the night
and mowing down tired,
outnumbered Baratheons
is the same as facing a prepared
Nd provisioned Lannister army?
No.
A reckoning will come.
We need the North
to face it.
The entire North.
They won't back us
without Sansa Stark.
We no longer have
Sansa Stark.
You played
your games with her.
You played your games with
the heir to the Iron Islands
and now they're both gone.
I have a team of men after them
with some of my best hounds.
They won't get far.
I'm glad to hear it.
Without Sansa, you won't be able
to produce an heir.
And without an heir,
well...
let's hope
the maesters are right
and Lady Walda's
carrying a boy.
( dogs barking )
( barking continues )
( panting )
We can't stop.
( barking continues )
We have to cross here.
( gasps ) I can't.
It's the only way
to throw off the hounds.
But it's too cold. I can't.
I won't make it. I'll die.
I've seen what his hounds
do to a person.
This way is better.
( barking continues )
( gasping )
( shivering )
Over here.
Come on.
( shivering )
Sansa.
( dogs barking )
Man:
Tell them to settle down!
Stay here.
I'll lure them away.
No, I won't make it
without you.
You will.
Go north, only north.
Jon is Lord Commander
at Castle Black.
He'll help you.
( barking, howling )
( men shouting )
Man:
See somebody, eh?
- Man #2: There they are!
- Man #3: Get them!
Where is Lady Bolton?
- Dead.
- Liar.
Theon: She broke her leg
jumping from the ramparts.
I left her to die
in the snow.
( barking )
Got something!
Run!
( horse whinnies )
Man:
Hyah!
- ( dogs barking )
- ( men shouting )
( whimpering )
- ( horse whinnies )
- Man #2: Resist. Stay.
( growling, barking )
- ( barking continues )
- Man #2: Stay.
I can't wait to see what parts
Ramsay cuts off you this time.
( man #3 grunting )
( whimpering )
( horse whinnies )
Man #2:
Rider! Who is it?
- It's a bloody woman.
- ( shouts )
( whinnies )
( roars )
( grunts )
( groans )
( shouts )
( whinnies )
( neighs )
( groans )
( groaning )
No! Please!
( grunts )
( panting )
( squelches )
( gasping )
Lady Sansa, I offer
my services once again.
I will shield your back
and keep your counsel
and give my life
for yours if need be.
I swear it by the old gods
and the new.
And I vow...
that you shall always
have a place by my hearth
and...
Meat and mead
at my table.
...meat and mead
And I pledge to ask
no service of you
that might
bring you dishonor.
I swear it by the old gods
and the new.
Arise.
( seagulls screeching )
( door opens )
Handmaiden: Your Grace, I'm sorry
to disturb you.
A ship from Dorne
has sailed into the harbor.
Myrcella.
( seagull screeching )
( bell tolling )
Do you remember
the first time you saw a dead body?
Mother.
All I could think about
when she died
was what would happen
to her now.
Every day,
every night,
what does Mama
look like now?
Has she started
to bloat?
Has her skin
turned black?
Have her lips
peeled back from her teeth?
I think about locking
Myrcella in a crypt.
I think about her beautiful little face
starting to collapse.
Shh, shh.
Don't think about it.
I have to.
I have to. It's not right she has
to suffer alone.
She's not suffering.
She's gone.
No one can
hurt her anymore.
She was good.
From her first breath,
she was so sweet.
I don't know where
she came from.
She was nothing like me.
No meanness,
no jealousy, just good.
I know.
I thought if I could
make something so good,
so pure...
- maybe I'm not a monster.
- Listen-- listen to me.
She was my daughter
and I failed her.
No, I knew
this would happen.
The witch told me
years ago.
She promised me three children
and she promised me they'd die.
"And gold their shrouds."
Everything she said
came true.
You couldn't
have stopped it.
It's prophecy.
It's fate.
- You don't believe that.
- Of course I do.
You told me yourself
when Father died.
You said we had
to stay together.
You said people would try
to tear us apart, take what's ours.
That was a prophecy, too.
I didn't listen to you
and everything you said came true.
Fuck prophecy.
Fuck fate.
Fuck everyone
who isn't us.
We're the only ones
who matter,
the only ones
in this world.
And everything
they've taken from us,
we're going
to take back and more.
We're going to take
everything there is.
"The Seven Hells brim
with the souls of saintly men.
They scream in agony
and their shame is so great,
they do not feel
the flames,
for now they see
if not for a single sin
they concealed,
they were saved."
I'd like to see
my brother.
- Confess.
- Please.
How is he?
At least tell me that.
Confess.
I am the queen
and I demand to see my brother.
Sinners
don't make demands.
They make confessions.
( gasps )
( door opens )
Septa Unella.
( sighs )
Our other guests need you.
- ( gasps )
- There.
Septa Unella can be
overzealous at times.
I'll speak with her.
My brother,
can you tell me how he is?
It isn't Ser Loras
that brings me here.
Your husband
misses you dearly.
The love between a man
and wife is sacred.
It reflects the love
the gods have for all of us.
But sin leads us away
from the sacred.
And only confession
can purge sin.
I have nothing
to confess.
So you believe
you are pure?
Perfect?
Wholly without sin?
None of us are.
You have started
down the path.
But you have
many miles to go.
( door opens, closes )
I always envied Oberyn.
He lived.
He truly lived.
Sailed around the world.
Fought men
from every country.
Lay with the most
beautiful women alive.
- And men.
He experienced
everything
while I sat here
in Dorne
trying my best to keep my people
alive and well fed.
But that is life.
We each have our roles.
Oberyn was born
to be an adventurer.
And I was born to rule.
The gods
are not fools.
You would have been
a lousy adventurer.
And Oberyn, pfft,
he would have been
a terrible ruler.
Your mother is a brilliant woman,
you know that?
Maester:
Prince Doran.
The Princess Myrcella.
( gasping )
When was the last time
you left this palace?
You don't know
your own people.
- Their disgust for you.
- ( Doran coughing )
Elia Martell raped and murdered,
and you did nothing.
Oberyn Martell butchered,
You're not a Dornishman.
You're not our prince.
My son Trystane...
( scoffs )
Your son is weak
just like you.
And weak men will never
rule Dorne again.
I told you
I'm not hungry.
We're not here
to feed you.
We're here to kill you.
You want her
to do it or me?
We are family.
I don't want to hurt you.
Her or me?
You.
Good.
Smart boy.
You're a greedy bitch,
you know that?
( door opens, door closes )
Tyrion: We're never going to fix
what's wrong with this city
from the top
of an 800-foot pyramid.
We'll be fine.
We're dressed like
common merchants.
You walk
like a rich person.
You've spent a lot of time studying
the way rich people walk?
You walk as though the paving stones
were your personal property.
I used to steal from people
like you when I was a boy.
It's a good thing
you're not a boy anymore.
Because you
have no cock.
( baby fussing )
( speaking Valyrian )
She thinks you want
to eat her baby.
( speaking Valyrian )
( speaks Valyrian )
- Varys: Mhysa means mother in Valyrian.
- I know what mhysa means.
- Varys: Who wrote it?
- Hard to know.
Our queen is not as popular in Meereen
as she used to be.
The Sons of the Harpy?
Very possibly.
Daenerys Targaryen took away
their most valuable property,
told them human beings
weren't even property to begin with.
You can see why
they're unhappy.
Of course,
it could also
be the freed men.
( people speaking Valyrian )
( man speaking Valyrian )
Many of the former slaves feel
that Daenerys has abandoned them.
She did fly away on a dragon
and not come back.
It's a problem.
Fear has brought Meereen
to a standstill.
Whoever you are,
wherever you go,
someone in this city
wants to murder you.
We can't fight
an enemy we don't know.
The Sons of the Harpy
planned their attack
in the fighting pits
very carefully,
which means they take
orders from someone.
And have you started
looking for that someone?
My little birds
have already taken wing.
Soon they'll return,
singing songs of men in gold masks.
( men shouting
in Valyrian )
- ( people shouting )
- ( bell tolling )
- ( shouting continues )
- ( bell continues tolling )
Well, we won't be sailing
to Westeros anytime soon.
Goat?
Ram.
You think
our friend got him?
Don't know anything else
that can melt a ram's horn.
We're on the right
path, then.
Daario: Perhaps she's tired
of being queen.
I don't think
she likes it very much.
She's too smart
to like it.
Maybe she's flown
somewhere else,
somewhere far away
from men like us.
I've been
all over the world.
There's no escaping
men like us.
her, eh?
You keep coming back.
Why?
You know why.
Isn't it frustrating
wanting someone
who doesn't want you back?
Of course it is.
You're a romantic.
I admire that.
Sometimes I look at you
and I think,
"So that's what I'll be like
when I grow old."
If you grow old.
If I grow old.
I hope I do.
I want to see what
the world looks like
when she's done
conquering it.
So do I.
Daario:
Huh, an army?
Not an army.
A horde.
Dothraki?
They have her.
( people shouting )
- ( shouts in Dothraki )
- ( groans )
( speaking Dothraki )
( chuckles, kisses )
No.
( men laugh )
( chatter )
( distant dog barking )
Woman: But there has to be a price
to pay for everything.
Man: I know, but have you tried
telling him that?
( chatter continues )
Thank you.
Man: Who'd go there after what
happened to that Kingsguard?
- Man #2: Probably had it coming.
- Man: Maybe so,
but I'm not risking it.
- Man #2: Just can't do it.
- Man: All right.
Woman: Honesty as well.
He gets it.
( chatter continues )
Waif: Are you listening,
blind girl?
Do you hear them talking?
Do any of them
talk to you?
No.
So sad.
( coins jingle )
- ( groans )
- Stand and fight, blind girl.
I can't see.
That's your problem,
not mine.
( groans )
( grunts )
( panting )
See you tomorrow.
( growling )
( pounding )
Ser Davos, we have
no cause to fight.
We are both
anointed knights.
Hear that, lads?
Nothing to fear.
Alliser: I will grant amnesty
to all brothers
who throw down their arms
before nightfall.
And you, Ser Davos,
I will allow you to travel south
a free man
with a fresh horse.
Davos:
And some mutton.
I'd like some mutton.
- What?
- I'm not much of a hunter.
I'll need some food if I'm gonna make it
south without starving.
We'll give you food.
You can bring the Red Woman
with you if you like.
Or you can leave her here with us,
whichever you choose.
But surrender by nightfall
or this ends with blood.
Thank you, Ser Alliser.
We'll discuss amongst ourselves
and come back to you with an answer.
( footsteps departing )
Boys, I've been running
from men like that all my life.
In my learned opinion,
we open that door--
And they'll
slaughter us all.
They want to come in,
they're gonna come in.
Aye, but we don't need
to make it easy for them.
Edd is our only chance.
It's a sad fucking statement
if Dolorous Edd is our only chance.
There's always
the Red Woman.
What's one redhead gonna do
against 40 armed men?
You haven't seen her do
what I've seen her do.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
( music playing )
♪ Music playing ends  ♪